Kai Chuen Tan

(614) 806-7342 | kctan@ucsd.edu | linkedin.com/in/kaichuentan/ | github.com/kaitheuser | San Diego, California

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a robotics engineer and enthusiast, who has more than 3 years of working experience in embedded software programming, designing mechanical systems, and industrial prototyping, with a profound interest in both computer vision and machine learning.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego (UCSD)

San Diego, CA

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering (Intelligent Systems, Robotics, and Control)

Dec 2022

The Ohio State University (tOSU)

Columbus, OH

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Dec 2019

• Awards : Graduated with Summa Cum Laude, Dean's List, Honors Research Distinction.

• Thesis : Development of Fully Autonomous and Cooperative Robotic System for Interplanetary Explorations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Autonomous Vehicle Laboratory, UCSD

San Diego, CA

Graduate Research Assistant (Perception and Motion Planning)

Jun 2022 - Present

• Developed a 3D-LiDAR annotation tool with a built-in .pcd to .bin file converter for data extraction and labeling.

• Implementing a real-time motion planning algorithm for a micro-mobility vehicle in a dynamic campus environment. **Advanced Skills:** Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, C++, Autoware, Docker, ROS, Linux, Git

Aonic (Formerly Poladrone Solutions Sdn. Bhd.)

Cyberjaya, Malaysia Sep 2020 – Aug 2021

Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) Engineer

- Implemented a drone speed parameter estimation algorithm using kinematics equations that improved the cost-efficiency of agriculture drone pesticide spraying missions by at least 10.1 %.
- Integrated the Hall-effect turbine flowmeter and water detection sensor into the Oryctes drone ecosystem to reduce the pesticide spraying volume error to less than 1.0 %.
- Designed and built Oryctes Dual and Mist agriculture drones' accessories that increased the pesticide spraying precision for Malaysia's largest plantation companies (i.e., Sime Darby Plantation, and Genting Plantations).
- Saved 39.2% of manufacturing cost by improving Oryctes' proximity sensors and gimbal camera mountings' structural design. Advanced Skills: C++, Python, PlatformIO, Git, Mission Planner, Ardupilot, SolidWorks, 3D-printing, Laser-cutting, GD&T

Automation and Optimization Laboratory, tOSU

Columbus, OH

Robotics Research Assistant

Aug 2018 - July 2020

- Decreased the computational cost of a heuristic-based path planning algorithm refined RRT* by 52 %.
- Saved at least 92 % of unmanned ground vehicles (UGVs) energy consumption in a rugged 3D-space exploration mission by integrating a jumping mechanism on customizable UGVs.
- Formulated multiple traveling salesman problem (mTSP) mathematically with a UGV's energy consumption model as a mixed-integer linear programming (MILP) to allocate UGV's visiting tasks efficiently.
- Reduced the weight of a UGV with a cam-follower jumping mechanism by 53 grams to increase power efficiency by designing a light and compact printed circuit board and tweaking the UGV's chassis design.

Advanced Skills: MATLAB, Python, C++, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, SolidWorks, Fritzing, 3D-printing, Laser-cutting, Machining

PROJECTS

Autonomous Vehicle Particle Filter and Visual-Inertial SLAM (Skills: Python, OpenCV, Matplotlib, NumPy, Sci-kit Learn)

• Localized the autonomous vehicle, performed landmark mapping using the EKF, and built a 2-D occupancy grid map of the environment given the odometry, 2-D LiDAR scans, and stereo camera data by using various SLAM techniques.

Therapeutic Robotic Interactive Canine Companion Robot (TRICC) (Skills: C++, Arduino, SolidWorks, 3D-printing)

• Designed and built an interactive and lovable companion robotic pet dog with a customizable and detachable busy blanket to provide sensory stimulation and soothing effects to people with dementia by reacting to a user's petting like a real dog.

TECH SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C++, C, MATLAB, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Swift

Frameworks

Concepts

CAD/Manufacturing
Relevant Courseworks

CopenCV, NumPy, Matplotlib, Sci-kit Learn, Pandas, Tkinter, Flask, TensorFlow, Pytorch
ROS, Git, Docker, Jupyter Notebook, LabVIEW, Simulink, Minitab, LaTeX, Microsoft Office
Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Robotics, Perception, Motion Planning, Big Data Analytics
SolidWorks, ANSYS ADPL, Abaqus, CATIA, CNC, GD&T, Laser-cutting, 3D-printing, Machining
Computer Vision, Sensing and Estimation in Robotics, Healthcare Robotics, Autonomous Driving

and Driver Assistance Systems, Robot Motion Planning, Programming for Data Analysis, CAD & Manufacturing

PUBLICATIONS

- M. Jung, K. Chuen Tan, and R. Dai, "Path Planning for a Jumping Rover Team with a Charging Station in Multi-waypoints Visiting Missions," Frontiers in Control Engineering, vol. 3, 2022.
- K. C. Tan, I. Shyu, M. Jung, C. Wan, and R. Dai, "Motion Planning and Task Allocation for A Jumping Rover Team," 2020 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2020.